# ZHEYUN FENG

+1 (517)-580-9065 \$\display\$ fengzheyun@gmail.com \$\display\$ http://www.cse.msu.edu/~fengzhey 57 Middlevale Rd Apt 1448A, East Lansing, MI, 48823

#### **SUMMARY**

With six years of research experience in Machine Learning, Data Mining/Analysis, Statistical Modeling and Information Retrieval. With publications on top conferences (ICCV and ECCV).

Interested in full-time researcher or engineer positions in relevant areas starting from September.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Ph.D. Computer Science

Aug.2011-Aug.2015(Expected)

Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI, USA.

Thesis: Large Scale Image Annotation and Noisy Tag Recovery.

Adviser: Prof. Rong Jin. GPA: 3.875

# M.E. (Ingénieur) Signal and Image Processing

Sep.2009-Jul.2011

Telecom Paris Tech (École Nationale Supérieure des Télécommunications), Paris, France.

Awarded with Eiffel Excellence Scholarship, the highest honor for international students.

# B.S. Electrical Science and Engineering

Sep.2005-Jun.2009

Nanjing University, Nanjing, China.

Graduated with Honors. Major GPA: 91/100, ranked 3 out of 89.

## EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCES

#### Research Assistant

Aug. 2011 - present

LINKS Lab, Dept. of CSE, Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI

## Research Internship

May 2013 - Aug. 2013, May 2014 - Aug. 2014

Video Content Analysis Group, Comcast Labs DC

Washington, DC

#### Research Internship

Jul. 2010 - Jan. 2011

New Initiatives Lab, Cisco (NDS) FRANCE. Was granted first degree premium.

Paris, France.

#### SELECTED RESEARCH PROJECTS

#### Multi-label Classification and Noisy Tag/Label Recovery

2012 - present

- Developed an *efficient kernel metric learning* algorithm to capture feature similarity.
- Developed an efficient robust matrix completion algorithm to recover missing and remove noisy tags (labels).
- Improved efficiency by approximating kernels and solving convex optimization problem.
- Provided theoretical guarantees with statistical error bounds.
- Accuracy improved 5% by comparing with state-of-the-art image tagging algorithms.
- Algorithms were applicable to document/image/audio/video tagging and multi-label classification.

# Multimedia Data Processing and Content Analysis

2010, 2013, 2014

Industrial intern projects in Comcast Labs DC and Cisco (NDS) France

- Developed an online application to detect and recognize commercials (advertisements) in TV Programs.
- Video(image, audio and subtitle) decoding/processing, feature extraction and synchronization.
- Accomplished text, logo, time/score ticker, face detection and recognition.
- Applied semi-supervised ensemble classification to identify the commercials.
- Achieved precision 98.6%, recall 98.4% on 102 videos, 20% higher than commercial tool Comskip.

## Large-scale Document Retrieval and Query Expansion

05/2012 - 09/2012

• Improved retrieval performance by improving similarity scoring and applying query expansion.

## Data classification and clustering

10/2012 - 04/2015

- Developed an effective algorithm to analyze the customer data and predict the business risk.
- Proposed a fast stochastic gradient descent method to solve high dimensional classification problem.
- Developed an ensemble classifier to classify 1K Synsets of ImageNet images, with accuracy of 91%.
- Developed a genetic algorithm to cluster large-scale high dimensional data from UCI datasets.

## Large-scale Information Search in High Dimensional Space

10/2011 - 05/2012

- Converted a high dimensional search to a sequence of one dimensional search with random projection.
- Derived an efficient kernel based vector representation for images to promote the computation.

# Image Processing and Analysis

2008, 2009 - 2011

- Performed cardiac MRI alignment with tagging lines, and reconstructed 3D cardiac deformation model.
- Segmented cytological/histological images, clustered and detected cancer cellular or abnormal tissue.
- Transferred color between photos, and corrected rendering color in certain clusters.
- Developed a fingerprint recognition system, with image processing, enhancement and matching skills.

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Zheyun Feng, Rong Jin and Anil K. Jain. Large-scale Image Annotation by Efficient and Robust Kernel Metric Learning. In International Conference of Computer Vision (ICCV),pp. 1609-1616, 2013.
- **Zheyun Feng**, Songhe Feng, Rong Jin and Anil K. Jain. *Image Tag Completion by Noisy Matrix Recovery* In European Conference of Computer Vision (ECCV), pp. 424-438, 2014.
- Songhe Feng, **Zheyun Feng**, and Rong Jin. Learning to Rank Image Tags with Limited Training Examples In IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, Vol. 24, NO. 4, April 2015.
- Zheyun Feng, Rong Jin and Anil K. Jain. Large-scale Image Tagging based on Noisy Matrix Completion (Preprint) Ready to submit to IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence.

## **ACTIVITIES**

Paper Reviewer AAAI 2015

Teaching Assistant CSE484 Information Retrieval, Fall 2013, MSU

Google Code Jam 2014 Full score 90/90 in Qualification round, ranked 1,613 out of 30K

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages C/C++ (10 years), Java (5 years), Matlab (8 years), Python (2 years),

Scala, Octave, Perl, R, MySQL, Javascript, HTML, Assembly Language scikit-learn, OpenCV, Lucene, FFMPEG, XML, JSON, OpenGL, Weka,

Hadoop, MapReduce, Spark, HPCC, GitHub, SVN, Kate, Emacs, Vim

Languages English, Chinese, French

#### SELECTED GRADUATE COURSES

▶ Machine Learning

Tools & Protocols

▶ Pattern Recognition & Analysis

▷ Computer Vision

▷ Data Mining

▶ Natural Language Processing and Interaction

▶ Multimedia Indexing and Retrieval

▶ Design & Theory of Algorithms

▶ Signal and Audio Processing

▶ Image Analysis and Reasoning

▶ Probability

▶ Evolutionary Computation

▶ Advanced Computer Graphics